Fabiano da Rosa Gomes

Software Engineer

I am a professional with over 9 years of experience in the field systems development and integration.

I worked in the development of embedded systems, creation of APIs, web frontend and desktop systems.

I am currently part of a multidisciplinary team that takes care of integration of clinical analysis equipment with several systems existing in laboratories and hospitals.

Contact

Address

Porto Alegre, Brazil

Phone

55051995432916

E-mail

gomes.fdr@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/go mes-fdr

Website

https://gomes-fdr.github.io/

Skills

Operating Systems:

Linux: Fedora, Debian MS Windows

Virtualization:

Gnome Boxes VirtualBox Docker

Programming Languages:

C and C++

Python

Qt and GTK (toolkits)

SQL

Languages:

Portuguese native speaker English good listening and comprehension

Work History

Software Engineer at VFR Sistemas

Porto Alegre, Brazil (2019-Current)

- Bug fixes and enhancements in the legacy code.
- Contributions on new features and enhancements in the software design.
- Stack used: Qt C++, shell script, Postgres, Oracle, docker and git.

Software Engineer self employed

Porto Alegre, Brazil (2018-2019)

- Delivered and maintained scalable system architecture to support high-availability Internet site with various internal applications.
- Stack used: Python, Flask Framework, Postgres, dokku(mini-heroku),
 Vuejs, Bulma-css and git.

Software Engineer at Digicon SA

Gravataí, Brazil (2011-2019)

- Contributed on all stages of systems development lifecycle, from requirement gathering to production releases (Linux x86 and ARM)
- Bug fixes and performance optimizations.
- Stack used: C, C++, GTK, GDB, shell script, sqlite, Lua, Python, and SVN.

Education

2014-2017 Associate Degree in Applied Science: Information Technology

Faculdade Senac De Tecnologia - Porto Alegre, RS